Jordan Fichter

Arlington, TX 76017 jordanfichter.work@gmail.com GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Detail-driven and tech-savvy professional with 7+ years of experience helping companies streamline personnel operations and security management. Possess two active federal security clearances. Knowledgeable of Adobe Cloud Creative, Figma, Atlassian, Office 365, and more! Looking to combine my passions for graphic design and technology into a role such as Web Design and/or UX Design, Programming, Business Analyst, or Project Management.

EDUCATION

University of North Texas, Jan. 2015 – June 2016 Fine Arts, Drawing, and Painting

Denton, TX

Tarrant County College, Aug. 2013 – June 2018

Fort Worth, TX

Art

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND SOFTWARE PROFICIENCIES

Responsive Web Design • GitHub • JIRA/Atlassian • Web Development • UI/UX Design • Email Marketing • Microsoft Office 365 • Figma • Adobe Creative Suite • Google Analytics • Google Docs • NeonCRM • Uplink • Quality Assurance • Troubleshooting • JavaScript Data Algorithms and Data Structures (in progress) • Scientific Computing with Python (in progress)

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

August 2022

Powerhouse Training Manual

Crowley, TX

Created end-user documentation for internal and external employees, including Powerhouse vendors.

- Assumed role for the creation of learning resources, overseeing framework, training, and maintenance.
 - Utilized Lucidchart to create flow charts that demonstrated the execution and steps of our project management software.

July 2022 — Present

Freelance Graphic Design

Arlington, TX

- Design and develop engaging graphic elements for client websites, social media platforms, and product packaging, including custom logos and illustrations.
- Collaborate with clients to develop engaging graphic design solutions based on market trends, brand identity, and target demographics.
- Supported the design of logos, brochures, and product packaging for multiple clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

February 2023 – Present

University of Texas at Arlington

Arlington, TX

College of Engineering - Department of Electrical Engineering

Administrative Assistant/Project Coordinator

- Assessed and analyzed student retention rates with a focus on transfer and first-time-in-college (FTIC) students.
- Tracked, analyzed, and reported KPIs on social media platforms. Created engaging content such as photos, flyers, and email campaigns. Proofread and edit content before publishing. Ensure content aligns with SEO strategies.
- Maintained contact lists between the Electrical Engineering department and the Career and Technical Educators.
 Preparing reports, presentations, and content creation.

March 2019 – Present

Self-Employed

Arlington, TX

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer

Experienced freelance web designer, programmer, and content creator with a focus on UX/UI design.

Conceptualizes web-based application design and mobile development optimization.

 Developed webpage landing functionalities. Designed, built, and maintained websites using authoring or scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media on domains such as Squarespace, WordPress, and WIX.

October 2022 – December 2022

U.S. Army

Fort Leonard Wood, MO

Signals Collection Analyst (35S)

Rank: E-3 — Private First Class

- Leadership, Reliability, Discipline
- Land Navigation
- Field Preparation

Gather clues from radio frequencies and electronic signals to detect and collect coded foreign intelligence messages. Intercept and identify these nonverbal frequencies and keep logs to piece together secret tactical messages.

May 2022 – August 2022

the*gameHERs

Remote, TX

Ambassador Community Manager

A temporary contract position spent working with a gaming start-up

- Monitored app & brand ambassador engagement.
- Organized and conducted interviews for potential ambassadors, and onboarding processes.
- Data curation and report creation for Stakeholders

June 2021 – June 2022

Powerhouse Retail Services, LLC

Crowley, TX

IT Specialist

QA Tester & Junior Software Developer

- Provided "spot training" for desktop, mobile, and web-based applications.
- Providing the initial prioritization of new development requests or issues, based on customer feedback or departmental impact.
- Assists the development team with application quality assurance by testing changes and enhancements prior to production release using JIRA.
- Troubleshooting and analyzing any reported bugs or issues with applications or systems from internal and external employees.
- Delivered UI/UIX-built projects by designing websites, producing process flows, and refining and documenting specs.

April 2019 – April 2020

XL & Associates

Farmers Branch, TX

Personnel Security Assistant

Private Contractor for the Department of Homeland Security

- Ordered and received background investigation products from the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), contracted service providers, and other federal agencies.
- Federal Data Facts Background Screening
- Case management

ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

Responsive Web Design Certification 11/2020 — freeCodeCamp • Fortinet NSE Information Security Awareness Certification 07/2022 — IBM • UX Design Certification 12/2022 — Austin Peay State University • SCLA Honor Society